<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker Chrome on Kanti Jadia</title>
    <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/docker-chrome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker Chrome on Kanti Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 08:41:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/docker-chrome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome in Docker</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/google-chrome-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 08:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/google-chrome-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker and the way to build an automated container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker has been in the news recently.For the uninitiated , Docker is containers on top of the Linux kernel.
It specifically deals with automation of software deployments using software containers.You can also look at docker as chroot++.
chroot on Unix operating systems is an operation that changes the apparent root directory for the current running process and its children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets look at a comparison between docker and Virtual Machines (VM).With x86 virtualization being the norm in modern data centers and cloud providers , its but apparent to do this.
On a physical machine , you create a set of VMs using KVM,VMware or XEN hypervisor etc.The number of VMs actually represent equivalent physical abstracts.Each VM represnts a full machine.
Containers are in a different paradigm.You create only that parts of the system , which you will actually need.With docker you could have 10x number of applications running on the same hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets dwell into the  specifics of a docker build.
The three basic items needed are
- The linux kernel with docker engine to run the build
- The Dockerfile ( the script which defines the application as well as all the dependencies needed for the application)
- The build process to spin a container (image) and ability to move it across systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any recent linux distribution like ubuntu , centos etc would have docker available for install.The latest version is Docker 1.81 as of this writing.
The Dockerfile is the secret sauce.It helps you put together the application image.The more intricate the Dockerfile , the more amount of work would be done.Keep it simple and efficient.
You actually have to program the Dockerfile.It has a specific sequence and artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the questions popping on my mind was ability to run Graphical ( X based) UI in Docker.Today I got a little chance to do it and the result is at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkantihub/docker-chrome&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jkantihub/docker-chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look forward to some feedback on the post and any questions which you may have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@code is under a free license&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>