<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kanti Jadia</title>
    <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kanti Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 08:41:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jkantihub.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome in Docker</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/google-chrome-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 08:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/google-chrome-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker and the way to build an automated container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker has been in the news recently.For the uninitiated , Docker is containers on top of the Linux kernel.
It specifically deals with automation of software deployments using software containers.You can also look at docker as chroot++.
chroot on Unix operating systems is an operation that changes the apparent root directory for the current running process and its children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets look at a comparison between docker and Virtual Machines (VM).With x86 virtualization being the norm in modern data centers and cloud providers , its but apparent to do this.
On a physical machine , you create a set of VMs using KVM,VMware or XEN hypervisor etc.The number of VMs actually represent equivalent physical abstracts.Each VM represnts a full machine.
Containers are in a different paradigm.You create only that parts of the system , which you will actually need.With docker you could have 10x number of applications running on the same hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets dwell into the  specifics of a docker build.
The three basic items needed are
- The linux kernel with docker engine to run the build
- The Dockerfile ( the script which defines the application as well as all the dependencies needed for the application)
- The build process to spin a container (image) and ability to move it across systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any recent linux distribution like ubuntu , centos etc would have docker available for install.The latest version is Docker 1.81 as of this writing.
The Dockerfile is the secret sauce.It helps you put together the application image.The more intricate the Dockerfile , the more amount of work would be done.Keep it simple and efficient.
You actually have to program the Dockerfile.It has a specific sequence and artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the questions popping on my mind was ability to run Graphical ( X based) UI in Docker.Today I got a little chance to do it and the result is at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkantihub/docker-chrome&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jkantihub/docker-chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look forward to some feedback on the post and any questions which you may have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@code is under a free license&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The search for information ...</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/the-search-for-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 19:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/the-search-for-information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anybody who has used google search has a little understanding of search.When google launched gmail a few years back , the idea was to have search + mail and the result is for all to see.Gmail is one of the most popular mail applications.
I have used google desktop search in its hay days and would like to admit that with the amount of information one needs to look up , desktop search was a very good option.With the amount of information shared with you increasing on a daily basis , it is but obvious that you need to search.DocFetcher came to my rescue a lot of times but it still needs a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching is a bit different from cataloging and looking up.If you have organized data it is easier to remember where to look and where to find.With a surge of unconditional data growth and lot of disorganized data we keep talking about BigData.BigData in itself is not something new , it has existed from the days of computer evolution or for that matter from the time the printing press was invented.The idea here is to say Bigdata is data which exists in not so organized format.
The real challenge for bigdata today is to organize and search it while making business sense out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I became aware that DocFetcher it was quite evident to me that Lucene engine is something very powerful.It has capabilities which can be very well applied to BigData problems.
Lets say you have a hadoop solution which you want to use as a search indexing.This can be accomplished using the Katta project.“Katta is a scalable, failure tolerant, distributed, data storage for real time access.” What I like the most about the Katta project is that it is the same do it yourself as in the early days of FOSS.
The other proejct which caught my attention is Apache Solr.This is again an enterprise search application.Solr has some RESTFul api’s as well which makes it easy for cloud based deployments.Apache Nutch is also one very good search application which can be combined with Hadoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docfetcher.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;http://docfetcher.sourceforge.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lucene.apache.org&#34;&gt;http://lucene.apache.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lucene.apache.org/solr&#34;&gt;http://lucene.apache.org/solr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hadoop.apache.org&#34;&gt;http://hadoop.apache.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nutch.apache.org/&#34;&gt;http://nutch.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_data&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How not to be a Computer Engineer.</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/how-not-to-be-a-computer-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 12:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/how-not-to-be-a-computer-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some stories have to be told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of a exercise at home , I was recollecting my earliest impressions of a computer.This brought an interesting reflection to me as to why should I not write a brief on my computing background.So here it is for your reading pleasure.By doing this , my intention is to only tell about things which formed my basis to be a computer engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first visual image of something connected to computers was from the punch cards which we had lying around in our house.My Dad , a BITS Pilani and Roorkee alumnus , used to program computers in the BITS computer center using punch cards.These punch cards stacked in an old almirah were there in our house for a considerable portion of our childhood.
The pungent smell they used to emanate clearly reflected the aging on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] Punch cards used to program mainframes.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/9kVvjpgV1-XYHPs7MWwzRrZTxBX_clIGoduz4XgDch9OZ1vAGWc3rA4aTFmnaXapfI9auLaHNDH4QXEpWuvzmFd6x3Q1kRhR2TE8B0oenGdHzRW_wf8&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second visual was from a handheld programmable computer which my Dad had bought from his office (somebody had brought it from Japan) for some work.This handheld device was a casio FX series pocket computer which had programmable controls.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;which had programmable controls.We made a small picture of Mahatma Gandhi to see if we could do some programming on this device.It was one of the possibilities on the device apart from being able to print as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three kids at home were super excited and in the melee , we dropped that device to the floor.The LCD screen blacked out partially and that image is edged in my memory from that day onwards.This broken computer was also lying in our house for a long time.My father working for TCE ( Tata Consulting Engineers ) later to be called TCS had to take it in the stride because of this.I don’t have the details as to why we never returned that broken device or what happened after this , but this was the first real computer which i saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]Casio programmable pocket computer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casio_FX-702P&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casio_FX-702P&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/UkmRv2lM5DMCdTQFFqOGzJw_1eXlJ5pR0JjBmIgimPyZfPy-kzcEpILyyDmHD90sIoBrkVrVSFqTeXp2J2Z39PjK9B97SxaZ5fHT3am4I1YND0EyaUo&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these two incidents above I was merely a spectator and not the guy in action.I don&amp;rsquo;t really know who of us dropped that device to this day.Those early days of school are still fresh in my mind and have a big impact on how I am.I was never in the list of top scorers and being the youngest sibling was more of a pampered kid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching Taare Zameen Par a few years back brought my earliest memories back.In fact i could associate with it a lot.We used to live in Yoginagar area of Borivali , Bombay (now Mumbai) and I used to study in S.S.Ajmera school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] The earliest photo which I have for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jkanti.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/23022007.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jkanti.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/23022007.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SSAjmera Kanti Jadia&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We subsequently moved to Nagpur a few years later and I started my studies in a school in Nagpur.My elder brother could not get admission in the same school and had to opt for a fairly low grade school for that one year.Later my brother also got admission to St.John&amp;rsquo;s in his 10th standard.I was on cloud nine those days.I would brag to my classmates how I got to play football with the 10th graders in lunch time.I was still in 5th standard and my elder brother in the highest grade of 10th.My brother subsequently moved on to SFS college ,Sadar where he was preparing for BITS Pilani entrance along with his studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile in the school we had some computers installed.These were done by engineers from HCL and the computer instructor came from Delhi.These set of computer used to be 80286 and 80386 computers on which we were allowed to play games at times.We were taught DOS,Basic and fundamentals of computer at the time.The recollection on these computers brings to my mind the Mario game which was very popular at that time.This game in fact was the one which we were allowed to play.We had these computer classes for about an year or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the way things progressed , my Dad in a conversation set it up that you should do polytechnic and become a Diploma Engineer.A series of events later I ended up taking admission to Diploma in Computer Engineering course in 1995.As part of the studies we had the exposure to the computer lab for our lab courses only.No free access to computers , no personal computers at our disposal at home.Learning computer engineering was more of a theoretical exercise than a practice oriented one.The only lab exercises were for C programming, microprocessor programming etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of the lab&amp;rsquo;s one 8085 programmable device got stolen and all the students were further restricted on the access to computer hardware or devices.The stolen device was later found but still the access to computer labs was still limited.All the students opted for extra coaching from outside teachers in order to score good marks but my financial ability was limited at that time and thus had to contend with the limited books I had access to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final year of the course computer engineering course I could get some liberty in opting for tuition&amp;rsquo;s.It had very good effect of the extra coaching as the coach was a very seasoned professional.This extra coaching had a very positive effect on the way I worked with computers later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing , I took some odd jobs in the first few months after Diploma and finally landed in a company in December 1998.In the journey of FOSS[5] , I have already detailed on how I got inclined towards GNU/Linux and other aspects of FOSS.Here let me add the other bits of the stories on Java ,Oracle etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java as a language was popularized and marketed pretty well in the late nineties.Working as a partner for Oracle in the local market our company was looking at getting some web connectivity to Oracle database.There was a discussion as  to whether we should go for web enabled projects or web based projects.The demarcation being , existing applications when run through the web browser after limited modifications would be web enabled , and the new ones which are written using html , php , java from scratch would be web based.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important factor for me was to either to continue as an administrator or program and become a developer.I started of with an idea of a project management system(pms) which would be used in house in the office for managing projects.I was free to choose whichever language or technology I wanted , the only condition being that  it has to connect to a Oracle database in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would continue to do my consulting work in the day and whatever time was available used to be in office looking for ways to do other things.I configured the ISDN network to be shared on the network and would browse the internet being the admin as well.A few of the other developers used to also spend time in office due to the incentive of getting free connectivity.We even had a person starting off with chatting and subsequently ending it with a good happy family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came upon me that we would opt for java as the language to write the frontend and connect it to a oracle database.The PMS project was an excuse for me to try different things out and I took full liberty in exploring GNU/Linux instead.Officially if I would want to be part of the development team , i had to have to make this PMS project work and deliver on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realization that I would be coding in Java was not pleasent in my mind as there were still discussions on the various mailing list if java is really free.How it will be charged etc.The good part was that it was all available to download.So instead of running java on the windows machine , I instead opted for java on linux with blackdown jdk.Here I would like to point to the reader that its overlayed work and so it might not be possible to maintain chronology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the consulting jobs I would go about and around town trying to install odd software or fix broken things.I went to a factory near nagpur where they had a legacy wipro machine which had a disk crash losing major pieces of data.I went and was able to bring up the database.This was a big image boost and subsequently when the machine itself crashed we migrated the entire solution to one of the digital server (x86) with the same dumb terminals and forms 3.0  working.This was legacy unix.On another job I was tasked with a colleague of mine to try and install Oracle on SCO for a university.It was reported that there were already 3-4 attempts to install but had still failed as it was not getting completed.There also we tasted success and we go the solution done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We my day time consulting and work on network solutions , mail solutions etc , i was continuing to explore computing at its best.I went to defence establishments.I went to other cities.Went to remote areas as well.End of it whatever time I used to get , it was used in office to continue working on PMS.I joined a java course as well ( sponsored ) , which was run by a prominent professor from VNIT ( VRCE at that time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working on the various software peices , we were trying to find a way to web enable the legacy applications written in Oracle Forms.This was accelarated a bit when Forms 6.0 was launched with the web broker.It used CORBA and IIOP at that time.The initial release of the product was awful.We were able to run it finally but it was just not upto the mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PMS was developed and later formed the basis for a much larger project management solution.The initial version of PMS was written in Java entirely by me.I was able to deliver on php as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of promotions announced was put with MS IIS which crashed at the clients place within first one hour of operation.As an interim solution I had to put a php solution in place and it survived the load on that day.We had proven free software could scale at 100 feet out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearing the end of the year 2003 , I moved to Hyderabad ( subsequently Bangalore immediately after training) and started working here.This is how I became a Computer Engineer.More stories to follow later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright &amp;copy; 2012 Kanti Jadia
Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article are permitted
worldwide without royalty in any medium provided this notice is preserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casio_FX-702P&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casio_FX-702P&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photo &amp;ndash; todo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jkanti.wordpress.com/2012/05/09/free-software-journey-for-kanti-jadia/&#34;&gt;http://jkanti.wordpress.com/2012/05/09/free-software-journey-for-kanti-jadia/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your cause is bigger than mine. Really ???</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/your-cause-is-bigger-than-mine-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 16:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/your-cause-is-bigger-than-mine-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of times people get into a vicious cycle thinking they can do something. The only thing they merely do is make noise and more noise. The idea to work on a problem is not to make the problem bigger but to fix it. Mitigate it if that is what makes it go away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People adopt different means of resolving problems. They work out in the public to solve problems. They work in a set group of people. They build relationships which last. Alas a single man is not capable of solving all the problems. You need a team at times which is working towards the cause. You need sustained effort ( sometimes for years) to change perceptions. Having worked on a problem for years on end you might realize that you need a fresh start, a new perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are too many egos which you need to satisfy if you live your life on somebody&amp;rsquo;s perception. Better spend the efforts in solving the problem. As long as you can solve your own problems first , you can surely reach out to others and help. The fact of the matter is , no single issue is big enough to get the dedication of your entire life if it is not your problem as well. The itch in you has to be taken in the stride for the larger cause. People spend entire lives in search of that perfect solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where is cause is higher , the means also matter. The means which are used could appear incorrect at times but in the end the cause has to win. The result shows up. The efforts also show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open , Collaborative , Result Oriented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the words one should keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Software journey for Kanti Jadia</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/free-software-journey-for-kanti-jadia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 05:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/free-software-journey-for-kanti-jadia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Free Software journey for Kanti Jadia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the year 1997 there was a wave of GNU/Linux running in the tech circles.I was still in college and with a bunch of friends wanting to know what this buzz was about.We bought the latest edition of PC Quest ( the source of computer information in those days).This was probably the first few covers which had a CD which came along.
Since we as students did not have access to a computer which we could tweak we settled for magazine and read through the articles.These were early days and we did not have an understanding as to what we will be doing after graduating from college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once out of college I was still hunting for a job.Dabbling with different set of initial hurdles I landed a job at Micropro in December 1998.I was employed in the hardware division under the leadership of Mr.Meher Pophali.Working for a client where I had to reinstall the OS , I asked why reinstall the software if the problem can be solved.This inquisitive nature would come very handy to me later.The problem was not really solved as it was a proprietary OS and I did not have the necessary skills with OS specific software.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This incident led me to do software support more than to do hardware.I was designated to go to customer place and sort software problems.Problems like system not working,printer drivers not working , scanner not working and so on so forth.Slowly and steadily I got exposed to more complex piece of software which were not really written by one person.The concept of software companies and the way they do business became known to me.I got to know of software which needed a dongle to work.The dongle was in place so that at one time only one computer could be used to run the software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gradually I was put to resolve more complex issues which included installation/configuration and troubleshooting of oracle software,networking,novell, exchange and other products.Then at one point I got a request to install oracle on SCO.Meanwhile in our office there was somebody working on GNU/Linux.He had installed the software of Redhat 5.1 or 5.2.I got interested and wanted to install it myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old hats on this reader list who know about those days would remember how difficult it was to get things working on a GNU/Linux system.Still I was inclined to try things out.The person who had initiated this GNU/Linux churn in our office (Mr.Jitendra Pal) decided to leave micropro and there was a void created.The consulting which we were doing for a client with Pal sir was handed over to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started reading more and more about GNU/Linux.Building proxy server , mail server , web server etc.We built a backup server with Samba as well so that the users on the network could dump their files onto the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile , we got a new internet connection in our own office.I was designated to make internet connectivity available to everybody in office.I built a proxy server , a mail server systems , some backup solution and so on so forth.There was an incentive given in terms of open access to internet if you come to office a little bit early ( when you have limited resources you tend to put curbs ).There are a lot more interesting stories which I can tell , but leaving them so as not to digress from the topic.We had a series of projects which were executed using GNU/Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I read more and more about GNU/Linux I got acquainted with licensing aspect, the GPL and Apache license.This led me to delve further and at one point I thought about leaving my job and joining the Free Software foundation in India.I met Dr.Nagarjuna and expressed my desire to help the movement in my capacity.Those were early days for the FSF-I and a lot of things were happening around.The wave of software patents came and It was really needed to stop the patents amendment.The fight against software patents is an ongoing one and will continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gnunify happened in 2003 , and that was when we had discussions as to how some projects should move forward.I ran a report on gnunify which was widely circulated.[1]
Thanks to Niyam Bhushan ( the LL fame ) we got a nice logo and logotype for FSF-India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I moved to Bangalore and started interacting with other like minded people.I was looking at making FSF-I represent at the Linux Bangalore conference.Eventually in 2005 with the renamed FOSS.IN we were able to get something.Imagine , in 2003 people were asking what FSF-India does [2] and in 2005 we got dedicated space for a stall.I have fond memories of the time me , Praveen and others were working to put the stall up for FSF-India[3].This was a big event where I represented FSF-India as a volunteer.I have been a long time supporter of free software and would continue to be.This is also reflective in my professional career as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing on the journey , I am embarking on a new endeavor in my professional life.This one is going to make a few new frontiers again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ending this with words from Geetanjali.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where The Mind is Without Fear
From Rabindranath Tagore&amp;rsquo;s Geetanjali
——————————————————–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where the mind is without fear
And the head is held high
Where knowledge is free
Where the world has not been broken up
Into fragments by narrow domestic walls
Where words come out from the depth of truth
Where tireless striving stretches its arms towards perfection
Where the clear stream of reason has not lost its way
Into the dreary desert sand of dead habit
Where the mind is led forward by thee
Into ever-widening thought and action
Into that heaven of freedom, my Father, let my country awake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright &amp;copy; 2012 Kanti Nandkishore Jadia
Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article are permitted
worldwide without royalty in any medium provided this notice is preserved&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/ilug-goa/message/5678&#34;&gt;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/ilug-goa/message/5678&lt;/a&gt; - Gnunify 2003 - A report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/linux-bangalore-non-tech/message/2791&#34;&gt;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/linux-bangalore-non-tech/message/2791&lt;/a&gt; - What does FSF-India do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mmethsmalappuram.web4all.in/archives/fsf-friends/2005-December/003733.html&#34;&gt;http://mmethsmalappuram.web4all.in/archives/fsf-friends/2005-December/003733.html&lt;/a&gt;  - FOSS.IN 2005 - A report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/foss-in/message/1735&#34;&gt;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/foss-in/message/1735&lt;/a&gt; - FOSS.IN some suggestions on names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/8675&#34;&gt;http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/8675&lt;/a&gt; - The What, Why and When of Free Software in India&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox ESR -- the release for extended support</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/firefox-esr-the-release-for-extended-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 12:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/firefox-esr-the-release-for-extended-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a corporation and want to implement Mozilla Firefox as your preferred browser , you can do so with ease now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozilla has come up with a ESR release for all those people who need there own deployment cycle for quality testing etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oracle has certified Firefox ESR for the EBS deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.oracle.com/stevenChan/entry/firefox_extended_support_release_10&#34;&gt;https://blogs.oracle.com/stevenChan/entry/firefox_extended_support_release_10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an attachment on the initial release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/organizations/&#34;&gt;http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/organizations/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jkanti.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/firefox_esr1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jkanti.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/firefox_esr1.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nagpur Calling...</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/nagpur-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 06:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/nagpur-calling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nagpur Calling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 24th of Feb I was on a mission.A mission to know if Nagpur is calling or not.
The MIHAN SEZ project , the cornerstone of MADC for the Nagpur Airport was being promoted here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MIHAN project has been in existence for a good part of the last decade and comprises of a cargo hub with Airport and a SEZ with residential zone attached.The unique attributes of the project make it an ideal location in Central India offering immense possibilities of growth.The project aims to act as the catalyst in the growth of Central India ,providing the much needed
boost to the economic activity in and around Nagpur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets see what really happened at the event.The event was setup in Hotel Center Point in the central part of Nagpur.The distance of the MIHAN project from the hotel was not more than 10 km&amp;rsquo;s.The least in terms of access to an SEZ from the central part of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The VED council has done a very good act to put an excellent event in place  to promote the facilities and economic vitality of Nagpur.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first to come on the dias was Mr.Devendra Parekh, the head for VED Council.He summarized the need for Nagpur to becoming the leader in economic developement.He described the state of Nagpur from being a follower to a challenger,from being a challenger to being a leader.
Nagpur has a lot of positives in terms of development.It has an engineering pool  with about 20,000 graduates available every year.Then there are the regular graduates which amount to around 50,000 ready to access pool of talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next to take the stage was Rajiv Vaishnav.A keen person interested to see the opportunities Nagpur can offer.He identified that Nagpur has all the necessary ingredients to be a great IT/ITES destination.He also showed interest in the various initiatives being taken to make Nagpur a hub for IT/ITES operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then to be on the stage was the current vice chairman of MADC , Mr.U.P.S.Madan.Mr.Madan was pretty straightforward on whatever challenges he was facing.He clarified that the MIHAN project is all set with the best available infrastructure which is ready to boot.
He mentioned pretty clearly identified the last few issues and was more than happy with the progress.With the global slowdown global companies are hunting for good places to complement there operations in major cities and Nagpur is an ideal location to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next to take the stage was Mr.Nitin Raut, minister from the Govt of Maharashtra.He as well mentioned the facilities of Nagpur and prospects in terms of economic development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the inaugural speeches were done there were a few panel discussions  on the Opportunities and Advantage of Nagpur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panelist included Raghavendra K ( Vice President and Head - HR ,Infosys BPO) , Praveen Kamath Kumbla(Head Talent Acquisition, Wipro BPO)
Mr.Ajay Chaturvedi, CEO and Founder HarVa BPO(The rural , all-women BPO) and others.
Companies like Persistent Systems and ADCC infocad also had leading representatives.The idea of Nagpur becoming a first grade IT/ITES destination competing with other cities across the world was being shown with clear advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I was very satisfied to see the growth of Nagpur from being a small place to the 114th largest city in the world.I am thankful to my friends back in Nagpur for taking the initiative in showcasing the advantages of Nagpur in terms of returning and making Nagpur the next destination in the India growth story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growit link - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growit.in/nagpur-city/ved-nasscom-it-ites-conference-2012/311-nagpur-calling-conference-ends-on-a-promising-note.html&#34;&gt;http://www.growit.in/nagpur-city/ved-nasscom-it-ites-conference-2012/311-nagpur-calling-conference-ends-on-a-promising-note.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Ebusiness Suite Browser Certifications.</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/oracle-ebusiness-suite-browser-certifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 10:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/oracle-ebusiness-suite-browser-certifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently Oracle was looking for some feedback on browser usage.The recent Mozilla policy for browser certifications has put them in a dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.oracle.com/stevenChan/entry/survey_your_enterprise_plans_for&#34;&gt;http://blogs.oracle.com/stevenChan/entry/survey_your_enterprise_plans_for&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozilla is committing to releasing new Firefox versions &lt;a href=&#34;http://mozilla.github.com/process-releases/draft/development_specifics/&#34;&gt;every six weeks&lt;/a&gt;.  Mozilla released Firefox 5 this week.  With this release, Mozilla states that Firefox 4 is End-of-Life and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9217837/Mozilla_retires_Firefox_4_from_security_support&#34;&gt;will not receive any additional security updates&lt;/a&gt;.  In a comment thread posted to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mike.kaply.com/2011/06/23/understanding-the-corporate-impact/&#34;&gt;Mike Kaply&amp;rsquo;s blog article discussing these new Firefox policies&lt;/a&gt;, Asa Dotzler from Mozilla stated:&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my take on this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the point of upgrades , i would like to throw a case in point.Sometime ago the main website for Oracle Support (support.oracle.com) was moved to a flash enabled one.The site simply mentioned that it needs flash version &amp;ldquo;Adobe Flash Player 9.0.115 or above  to work&amp;rdquo;.Would this be right for Oracle to say that it needs 9.0.115 only as they certified the website only for this specific version of flash.I would doubt you would do that.You will instead say as long as the basic set of features we need to run this website are available we should be good to get past the version hell.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What i would instead want Oracle to do is to certify on the features( web standards) and than whatever browsers support the standards it would automatically work with the application ( EBS in this case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other question is on security updates.This I consider is more important to get by than the version hell.It might appear that the security updates would stop if certain versions of the software are not provided.Please provide 3 examples/points to me why Oracle still support IE6 and IE7 when the company producing it has went to IE9 and soon to be IE X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again refer back to the previous paragraph.Its better we talk about specific browser features than about specific versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since MS is dominant desktop platform today , we might think this is tied to the Operating System version and the upgrade cycle on the OS.Soon in the future with so many tablets and mobile phones (smartphones) around you will start building front ends for these diverse platforms(ipad,android,hp tablets etc).This would be prudent to say that this new set of Operating Systems would also vouch for part of the enterprise space.You will have to certify features on them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at this survey , we might be biased to say that upgrades need to planned and the browser is one thick block which is the gateway to the application.I would rather say the browser is the enabler.As long as it provides a certain set of features you should be okay to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drop me a personal mail if you think we can discuss it in some other ways.I always see Oracle as one company which can do a significant change in the IT Marketplace.Well change the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozilla is committed to providing the best Web experience for people everywhere, for whom the Web has become such an important part of their daily lives.  Providing updates to Firefox more frequently allows us to secure users against emerging threats and provide the platform for innovation that today’s rich and compelling Web experiences demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mozilla Community has focused our efforts on the needs of the individual user, and prioritized the product roadmap and features accordingly. However, as is the case with many technologies, loyal Firefox users and their IT departments, have sought to bring Firefox into their places of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mozilla.com/blog/2011/06/28/firefox-in-the-enterprise/&#34;&gt;http://blog.mozilla.com/blog/2011/06/28/firefox-in-the-enterprise/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Open Network</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/the-virtual-open-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 06:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/the-virtual-open-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent case of allowing access on open wifi routers got a person in the police network[1].His only problem was that he knowingly/unknowingly left his wifi router open for access.At one end of the side you can easily notice the innocence in the case,but if you look at it from the other angle its called a security hole.Anybody with sufficient malafide intent could simply play with this setup and cause problems for the person opening up his network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is this interesting preposition where EFF is encouraging you to share your wifi network[2].The request puts it in perspective as to how it would be a community good if we have had unconditional access to the Internet as you would for your basic rights.In Finland there is a legislation[3] which makes access to Internet a right for every citizen.The use of the Internet is not so common in third world countries but a survey conducted recently concludes
that Internet access helps people increase their knowledge, makes them more open to communication and is a public good.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we could create a network which would allow anyone access to Internet? What if it helped you keep the anonymity on the Internet intact?Imagine situations where you are on the road and need Internet access.You are stuck in a place where there is no standard telecom network.Hilly regions where you are on a trekking trip and find yourself disconnected[4].It would be a nice or must have situation where you want Internet access.To solve these issues we could put together a model which keeps the Internet open and accessible for the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The virtual open network is nothing but the intent to keep the Internet free for access.To make it omnipresent so that it is available anywhere and everywhere.The need for this is enormous , the technical challenge huge , but is it needed? yes it is.The Internet should be kept open.It should not be locked down by commercial interests and government control.It is part of your digital freedom.Make the Internet just about one more public utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of such a public network is not difficult to find.The electric network is one such example.Imagine a situation where your electricity provider makes it just about impossible for you to get electricity.The cost rise of electricity is just about impossible.Would you look for a way out? Would you opt for a different electricity provider? Yes , if you had that option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The need of the day is to ensure we keep the Internet open.We need to continuously thrive for it.We need to keep finding ways to leave it for easy accessibility.We need to keep it anonymous.We need to keep it free.We need to keep it open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=135680995&#34;&gt;NY Case Underscores Wi-Fi Privacy Dangers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2011/04/open-wireless-movement&#34;&gt;Why We Need An Open Wireless Movement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.loc.gov/lawweb/servlet/lloc_news?disp3_l205401633_text&#34;&gt;Finland: Broadband Access to Be a Legal Right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AirJaldi&#34;&gt;Rural wifi network in the Himalayas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://drupal.airjaldi.com/node/56&#34;&gt;The Dharamsala Community Wireless Mesh Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Dharamsala_flagtenna.jpg&#34;&gt;An AirJaldi node draped by Tibetan prayer flags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;What you learn in college will stick with you for the lifetime&#34;</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/what-you-learn-in-college-will-stick-with-you-for-the-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 06:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/what-you-learn-in-college-will-stick-with-you-for-the-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;College education is something at which point you are not mature enough to
understand everything but are mature enough to not able to understand at all.I
would like to give you a small story which happened to me many years ago.I was
sitting alone and pondering what i will do on my exams the next day.I was really
in thought if i faired miserably or had a bad day this would make a wreck
out of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here came along my elder brother who gave his mind out to me.He said
&amp;ldquo;What you learn in college will stick with you for the lifetime&amp;rdquo;.
The friends and colleagues you make may not be with you , the actual knowledge
will also not be with you.The important thing which will stay with you is the
application of this learning.You will apply the skills you learned in college for
many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of getting good college education thus gets exemplified.You need
to be rooted at all times and keep your feet on the ground.You need to make
optimal use of this opportunity and keep things in perspective.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now , how is this related to the opensource way.The way we comprehend knowledge
and the way it is shared is nearly the same way opensource works.
You get shared knowledge.You get information which has been passed on from
generations.You are in fact standing on the shoulders of giant&amp;rsquo;s and making
the knowledge commons work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very startling fact i discovered recently was the way Salman Khan from
Khanacademy is approaching this.He has successfully been putting together
videos which teach you from the basics to a lot of advance subjects.Subjects
which when learned as a new topic seem difficult at first.I am a big fan of the
Khan Academy.It paves the way for the learning to be self paced and in short
order.You need not sit for a long lecture in a crammed class trying to comprehend
what the professor/teacher just spoke.You keep yourself in the confines of a
comfortable environment and can pace the learning  at the same speed at which
you can comprehend and understand the best.You can always pause the video and
ask a few questions and than resume at the same point.The lessons are not in a
long boring format.Each of the videos is just paced right keeping it in the
confines of around 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this on what basis.He has licensed all his work under a CC license.Anybody
can make use of these lectures in the way they like.There already are so many
different people interested in Khan academy and the way it is working.Here is
wishing best of luck to Salman Khan and here are the three cheers for the
freedom way.The way to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference URL&amp;rsquo;s
Khan Academy - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khanacademy.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.khanacademy.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GnuCash 2.4.0 is out ,mysql ,postgresql,sqlite</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/gnucash-2-4-0-is-out-mysql-postgresqlsqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 12:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/gnucash-2-4-0-is-out-mysql-postgresqlsqlite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This has been a refreshing change for me.&lt;strong&gt;GnuCash&lt;/strong&gt; has been a very good personal accounting tool for me and I have enjoyed using it whenever needed.I have recommended it t a couple of people as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new feature which i am thrilled to use is connectivity to the database ( GDA ).This allows you to store the gnucash data in backend tables.You can use sqlite,mysql or postgresql to store the data.
Most of the gnucash business logic is still in the frontend and it would take some time for the complete makeover as I understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the database feature is pretty straight forward.If the option is compiled in your gnucash binary you will notice xml,mysql,postgresql as an option available when you do a &amp;ldquo;Save As&amp;rdquo; in the file menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_64&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;GnuCash database options&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://jkanti.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/gnucash_db.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jkanti.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/gnucash_db.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the data in the database it is really a matter of connecting and getting the reports in the formats you desire.
One limitation in the earlier versions was the need to understand &amp;ldquo;guile&amp;rdquo; to write reports for gnucash.But now it is just a matter of connecting to the backend and writing the reports.Come on jasperreports&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://lwn.net/Articles/421412/&#34;&gt;http://lwn.net/Articles/421412/&lt;/a&gt; &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Major changes in the 2.4.0 release include; 

      * In addition to the XML backend, Gnucash can now use a SQLite3,
        MySQL or PostgreSQL database to store the data. This is a new
        implementation using libdbi. It supports all features including
        the business features. In order to build with this, add
        --enable-dbi to the configure command. In addition to the
        libdbi-dev package for your distribution, you will also need the
        appropriate DBD (libdbi driver) package for sqlite3, mysql or
        postgresql.
      * As a replacement for the current GtkHTML HTML engine used to
        display reports and graphs, Gnucash can use WebKit. WebKit is
        the engine used by Google Chrome on Windows and Safari on Apple.
        In order to build with this, add --with-html-engine=webkit to
        the configure command. You will need an appropriate webkit-dev
        package. On win32, you will need to download the
        webkit-1.1.90-win32.zip file from the source repository and put
        it into the downloads directory of your gnucash build area.
      * Updated AqBanking on Win32.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chao&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress on Android</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/wordpress-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 21:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/wordpress-on-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the new release of wordpress I finally took the plunge.The application is great and very responsive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android and Mozilla</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/android-and-mozilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 13:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/android-and-mozilla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the first pre-alpha release of fennec for Google Android &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/mobile/&#34;&gt;fennec&lt;/a&gt; the mozilla gecko engine has finally arrived on android mobile devices.A lot of it is still to be fixed and I can only say that people will love to see gecko on mobiles officially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current port is a big 11MB download which i just tested on my emulator.Need some more push to put it on the actual device.With this the following are the browsers which i know are available for android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;google chrome mobile
opera mini
mozilla fennec&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I5700 Galaxy Spica - Samsung&#39;s Android phone</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/i5700-galaxy-spica-samsungs-android-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/i5700-galaxy-spica-samsungs-android-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This piece of hardware has pretty good specs.The stock software is android 1.5 with some additional samsung applications.
The spica is available in a lot of markets other than the US and at this price point ( 12k Rs) is a really attractive
offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once i got the phone , the first thing i tried to find is how i can update software on this phone.
The android market with its list of applications turned out to be a good head turner than going and looking
for applications for say a Symbian or Java enabled phone.
There is a small application call J2ME apps ( bundled by Samsung i suppose).This would possibly make installation
of J2ME applications also possible on the SPICA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The touch keyboard has two options , namely the default android keyboard and the samsung touch keyboard.
The key tapping is nice but not very good.Maybe it would take a while for me to get used to it.
I am still looking for alternate keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung announced that the SPICA would soon get a android 2.1 update and that would make it more useful.
I called up the Samsung customer care to find out and was told none of it is available in India yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SPICA phone is pretty bad at PC connectivity.The bundled NPS software from samsung does not support this phone.
Its not even detected properly if attached to a PC.Even after the proper drivers are installed , the official software
fails to recognize the phonebook, contacts or any other content on the phone.This would be one big reason why samsung android phones would not be lapped up by users at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had rockbox on my ipod for a long time and thus may pretty well get some other build installed on top of the
SPICA.With android being free software i only hope somebody comes up with stable builds for android 1.5 as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, I had resisted getting a smartphone for a long time and would like input on different ways i
could make use of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Weblogic Server 10.3.1 FMW 11g</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/oracle-weblogic-server-1031-fmw-11g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 06:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/oracle-weblogic-server-1031-fmw-11g/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Weblogic 10.3.1  install review for FMW 11g&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weblogic is the base java container for FMW 11g.The first piece of software you will put for any FMW 11g install.Oracle Weblogic Server is a collection of the application server,admin console and other components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I like about the install is the number of options you have.The install can be done online using the net installer or using the downloaded software.You have a text as well as gui based installer.You can also script the install for silent mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The install creates a middleware home for you.This will be the top level directory under which additional FMW 11g components would be installed.In weblogic , each OC4J container is now a domain.As you install the various components eg. Forms,Reports etc new domains get created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 108 different ways you could have Oracle Application Server 10g put into use.With Fusion Middleware 11g I can see much more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
