<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samsung on Kanti Jadia</title>
    <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/samsung/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Samsung on Kanti Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 23:42:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/samsung/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I5700 Galaxy Spica - Samsung&#39;s Android phone</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/i5700-galaxy-spica-samsungs-android-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/i5700-galaxy-spica-samsungs-android-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This piece of hardware has pretty good specs.The stock software is android 1.5 with some additional samsung applications.
The spica is available in a lot of markets other than the US and at this price point ( 12k Rs) is a really attractive
offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once i got the phone , the first thing i tried to find is how i can update software on this phone.
The android market with its list of applications turned out to be a good head turner than going and looking
for applications for say a Symbian or Java enabled phone.
There is a small application call J2ME apps ( bundled by Samsung i suppose).This would possibly make installation
of J2ME applications also possible on the SPICA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The touch keyboard has two options , namely the default android keyboard and the samsung touch keyboard.
The key tapping is nice but not very good.Maybe it would take a while for me to get used to it.
I am still looking for alternate keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung announced that the SPICA would soon get a android 2.1 update and that would make it more useful.
I called up the Samsung customer care to find out and was told none of it is available in India yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SPICA phone is pretty bad at PC connectivity.The bundled NPS software from samsung does not support this phone.
Its not even detected properly if attached to a PC.Even after the proper drivers are installed , the official software
fails to recognize the phonebook, contacts or any other content on the phone.This would be one big reason why samsung android phones would not be lapped up by users at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had rockbox on my ipod for a long time and thus may pretty well get some other build installed on top of the
SPICA.With android being free software i only hope somebody comes up with stable builds for android 1.5 as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, I had resisted getting a smartphone for a long time and would like input on different ways i
could make use of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>