<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Khan Academy on Kanti Jadia</title>
    <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/khan-academy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Khan Academy on Kanti Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 06:24:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/khan-academy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;What you learn in college will stick with you for the lifetime&#34;</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/what-you-learn-in-college-will-stick-with-you-for-the-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 06:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/what-you-learn-in-college-will-stick-with-you-for-the-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;College education is something at which point you are not mature enough to
understand everything but are mature enough to not able to understand at all.I
would like to give you a small story which happened to me many years ago.I was
sitting alone and pondering what i will do on my exams the next day.I was really
in thought if i faired miserably or had a bad day this would make a wreck
out of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here came along my elder brother who gave his mind out to me.He said
&amp;ldquo;What you learn in college will stick with you for the lifetime&amp;rdquo;.
The friends and colleagues you make may not be with you , the actual knowledge
will also not be with you.The important thing which will stay with you is the
application of this learning.You will apply the skills you learned in college for
many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of getting good college education thus gets exemplified.You need
to be rooted at all times and keep your feet on the ground.You need to make
optimal use of this opportunity and keep things in perspective.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now , how is this related to the opensource way.The way we comprehend knowledge
and the way it is shared is nearly the same way opensource works.
You get shared knowledge.You get information which has been passed on from
generations.You are in fact standing on the shoulders of giant&amp;rsquo;s and making
the knowledge commons work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very startling fact i discovered recently was the way Salman Khan from
Khanacademy is approaching this.He has successfully been putting together
videos which teach you from the basics to a lot of advance subjects.Subjects
which when learned as a new topic seem difficult at first.I am a big fan of the
Khan Academy.It paves the way for the learning to be self paced and in short
order.You need not sit for a long lecture in a crammed class trying to comprehend
what the professor/teacher just spoke.You keep yourself in the confines of a
comfortable environment and can pace the learning  at the same speed at which
you can comprehend and understand the best.You can always pause the video and
ask a few questions and than resume at the same point.The lessons are not in a
long boring format.Each of the videos is just paced right keeping it in the
confines of around 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this on what basis.He has licensed all his work under a CC license.Anybody
can make use of these lectures in the way they like.There already are so many
different people interested in Khan academy and the way it is working.Here is
wishing best of luck to Salman Khan and here are the three cheers for the
freedom way.The way to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference URL&amp;rsquo;s
Khan Academy - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khanacademy.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.khanacademy.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>