<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cause on Kanti Jadia</title>
    <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/cause/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cause on Kanti Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 16:37:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/cause/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Your cause is bigger than mine. Really ???</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/your-cause-is-bigger-than-mine-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 16:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/your-cause-is-bigger-than-mine-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of times people get into a vicious cycle thinking they can do something. The only thing they merely do is make noise and more noise. The idea to work on a problem is not to make the problem bigger but to fix it. Mitigate it if that is what makes it go away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People adopt different means of resolving problems. They work out in the public to solve problems. They work in a set group of people. They build relationships which last. Alas a single man is not capable of solving all the problems. You need a team at times which is working towards the cause. You need sustained effort ( sometimes for years) to change perceptions. Having worked on a problem for years on end you might realize that you need a fresh start, a new perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are too many egos which you need to satisfy if you live your life on somebody&amp;rsquo;s perception. Better spend the efforts in solving the problem. As long as you can solve your own problems first , you can surely reach out to others and help. The fact of the matter is , no single issue is big enough to get the dedication of your entire life if it is not your problem as well. The itch in you has to be taken in the stride for the larger cause. People spend entire lives in search of that perfect solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where is cause is higher , the means also matter. The means which are used could appear incorrect at times but in the end the cause has to win. The result shows up. The efforts also show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open , Collaborative , Result Oriented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the words one should keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>