<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gnucash on Kanti Jadia</title>
    <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/gnucash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gnucash on Kanti Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 12:06:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jkantihub.github.io/tags/gnucash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>GnuCash 2.4.0 is out ,mysql ,postgresql,sqlite</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/gnucash-2-4-0-is-out-mysql-postgresqlsqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 12:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/gnucash-2-4-0-is-out-mysql-postgresqlsqlite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This has been a refreshing change for me.&lt;strong&gt;GnuCash&lt;/strong&gt; has been a very good personal accounting tool for me and I have enjoyed using it whenever needed.I have recommended it t a couple of people as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new feature which i am thrilled to use is connectivity to the database ( GDA ).This allows you to store the gnucash data in backend tables.You can use sqlite,mysql or postgresql to store the data.
Most of the gnucash business logic is still in the frontend and it would take some time for the complete makeover as I understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the database feature is pretty straight forward.If the option is compiled in your gnucash binary you will notice xml,mysql,postgresql as an option available when you do a &amp;ldquo;Save As&amp;rdquo; in the file menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_64&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;GnuCash database options&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://jkanti.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/gnucash_db.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jkanti.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/gnucash_db.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the data in the database it is really a matter of connecting and getting the reports in the formats you desire.
One limitation in the earlier versions was the need to understand &amp;ldquo;guile&amp;rdquo; to write reports for gnucash.But now it is just a matter of connecting to the backend and writing the reports.Come on jasperreports&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://lwn.net/Articles/421412/&#34;&gt;http://lwn.net/Articles/421412/&lt;/a&gt; &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Major changes in the 2.4.0 release include; 

      * In addition to the XML backend, Gnucash can now use a SQLite3,
        MySQL or PostgreSQL database to store the data. This is a new
        implementation using libdbi. It supports all features including
        the business features. In order to build with this, add
        --enable-dbi to the configure command. In addition to the
        libdbi-dev package for your distribution, you will also need the
        appropriate DBD (libdbi driver) package for sqlite3, mysql or
        postgresql.
      * As a replacement for the current GtkHTML HTML engine used to
        display reports and graphs, Gnucash can use WebKit. WebKit is
        the engine used by Google Chrome on Windows and Safari on Apple.
        In order to build with this, add --with-html-engine=webkit to
        the configure command. You will need an appropriate webkit-dev
        package. On win32, you will need to download the
        webkit-1.1.90-win32.zip file from the source repository and put
        it into the downloads directory of your gnucash build area.
      * Updated AqBanking on Win32.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chao&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>