<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taare Zameen Par on Kanti Jadia</title>
    <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/categories/taare-zameen-par/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taare Zameen Par on Kanti Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 18:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jkantihub.github.io/categories/taare-zameen-par/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>From 6 to 60 , taare zameen par...</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/from-6-to-60-taare-zameen-par-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/from-6-to-60-taare-zameen-par-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today i went to watch the movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taare_Zameen_Par&#34;&gt;Taare Zameen Par&lt;/a&gt; ( TZP ).&lt;br /&gt;
Its a smart story of aspirations.To start with , i have not seen such a colourful movie in recent times.&lt;br /&gt;
The work done on the graphics by Tata Elxsi is good too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a small kid having dyslexia is forced to go through the rigorous&lt;br /&gt;
schedule of daily schooling he tends to rebel.Most of the times he&lt;br /&gt;
expresses his feelings in ways that his parents do not understand at first.&lt;br /&gt;
He is packed off to a boarding school to get some discipline and that is where&lt;br /&gt;
he gets to meet his wonderful arts teacher.&lt;br /&gt;
To admit it frankly that there is a problem in the way schooling is done&lt;br /&gt;
these days in most parts of our country is truly glorified.&lt;br /&gt;
The underlying statement is true , we are creating horses to run.&lt;br /&gt;
Run like anything , 95 , 96 , 97 and the points together makes the kids run and run and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What i liked most about this movie is the wonderful performance by the kid(Darsheel) in the movie.&lt;br /&gt;
The remarks by other teachers in the end makes things better for all of the other kids.&lt;br /&gt;
The film exemplifies the important points and brings home the real winners.&lt;br /&gt;
Winners of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Age really shows up on Aamir&amp;rsquo;s face but ultimately his performance rocks.&lt;br /&gt;
With this being his own production , it had to be a very good attempt.&lt;br /&gt;
Indeed it wins by all accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>