<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foss.In 2005 on Kanti Jadia</title>
    <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/categories/foss/index.in-2005/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foss.In 2005 on Kanti Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 08:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jkantihub.github.io/categories/foss.in-2005/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS.IN/2005 a report</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/fossin2005-a-report-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 08:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/fossin2005-a-report-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOSS.IN/2005 - Report&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thejadias.org/blog/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thejadias.org/blog/&#34;&gt;http://www.thejadias.org/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The event formally known as LB or LinuxBangalore got a new name and a new&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;venue this year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;What could be more appropriate than the historical Bangalore Palace to hold&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;the conference.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;We ( me and Praveen A ) had planned to put a stall for FSF-India at FOSS.IN.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I was never keen on putting a demo as i believe that the whole of FOSS.INdemoed&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Free Software a lot.A lot of it infact as this was FOSS.IN.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;We reached the venue on 29th Morning around 8:15.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Praveen had registered for a lot of volunteering and also helped some in the&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;conference as well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;He got in touch with Tejas and got right inside the registration counter to&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;help out.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;( &lt;a href=&#34;http://people.redhat.com/jmorris/images/fossinmisc2.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://people.redhat.com/jmorris/images/fossinmisc2.jpg&#34;&gt;http://people.redhat.com/jmorris/images/fossinmisc2.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Praveen wearing the &amp;ldquo;Freedom Matters&amp;rdquo; T-Shirt.Would upload the images in&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;some time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The format of the FOSS expo area was known to us and the idea of a stall was&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;a bit off.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I got myself registered as a delegate and headed straight to the FOSS Expo&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;area.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The FOSS Expo area had nobody in at that time so i headed to Intel hall (&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;750 seater ).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;As i was moving towards the hall i met Gaurav Nawani.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Gaurav mentioned that he would be putting up a demo of Blender in the FOSS&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Expo Area.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;He mentioned that he and his elder brother run a company (IronCode) and they&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;make games.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I enquired as to what kind of games they wrote and he mentioned casual&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;games.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The kind of games you enjoy playing in your liesure time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;We both went inside the hall and sat there for the opening to be announced&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The conference was opened with the lighting up of a lamp ( having five sides&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;) , traditionally&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;called a Samai ( Sa-Maa-eeee ), by representatives of various GLUGs across&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;India ( 5 ).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The conference theme was very well described by the following poem.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where The Mind is Without Fear&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;From Rabindranath Tagore&amp;rsquo;s Geetanjali&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;——————————————————–&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where the mind is without fear&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;And the head is held high&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where knowledge is free&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where the world has not been broken up&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Into fragments by narrow domestic walls&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where words come out from the depth of truth&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where tireless striving stretches its arms towards perfection&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where the clear stream of reason has not lost its way&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Into the dreary desert sand of dead habit&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where the mind is led forward by thee&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Into ever-widening thought and action&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Into that heaven of freedom, my Father, let my country awake&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The first keynote was given by Alan Cox on the relevance of getting involved&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;with Free Software.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The red coloured cap (hat) worn by Alan was quite evident and only when he&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;reached the end of the keynote did&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;he remove it.The cap was visible for all four days of the event and you were&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;sure to see Alan every once in a while.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The most interesting part of the talk for me was the part where he mentioned&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;that you can just&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;get involved with a web browser and an email account.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Where do you find this small a need to get involved with any sort of&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;project.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The benefits of working with FOSS projects are immense.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Apart from programming skills which you gain you get to know a lot of&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;different people.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;You learn how to interact with people from various cultures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Once the keynote by Alan got through i walked in straight to the FOSS Expo&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Area.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Karunakar was already there with 3 machines being put up for IndLinux&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;project.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Next to the IndLinux machines was a demo of LTSP put up by ILUG-DELHI guys.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Gaurav was along with me as well looking where to put his Blender&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;demo.Wegot 3 machines and got them unpacked.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I went ahead and put the GNU &amp;amp; Penguin sticker on one of the machines from&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;the ones i had.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;After a bit of groupalla ( get together ), we had the machines ready.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I had a couple of posters with me which and brouchers for FSF-India and&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;SPACE.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;A small lesson , do not expect to find gum/sticking/pins etc near the venue.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Saw Kartik Mistry putting the Debian poster and so ran out to get some&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;cellotape/pins from him.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;A lot of people were around including Karunakar,Jaldhar , Mahesh Pai, Gora&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Mohanty, Pramode&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;, Arjun etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;At around afternoon i saw Alan coming inside the FOSS Expo Area, and in a&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;few mins he was not to be seen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;After some time Atul appeared and requested that the FOSS Expo area would&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;also move to the Conference Expo area.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;We thought we would all move the out in the morning and than in a flash we&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;were all out that area.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;By this time Amol and Sameer came in too from Delhi.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;We got a dedicated stall for FSF-India and this meant we were back to where&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;we started.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;We got the machines in place and then got a few posters put as well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Anush was very keen on getting those posters as he felt they were very&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;impressive( Indeed they are ).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;All along the four days we were kind of doing a round robin on the FSF-India&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;stall.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Sometimes it was me , sometimes Amol, another time Sameer and offcourse&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Praveen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Praveen was sharing with me some details on the talks going on in the&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Ballroom as he was the hall marshal there.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;In all i attended around six/seven talks/bofs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The food was good with you paying in paper coupens(with options of&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;South/North Indian and Pizzas ).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The T-Shirt also was is good and i hope it hangs around upto next year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Am surprised at the low amount of information people have about FSF.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;People do not even know where gcc came from.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I was kind of letting people know about FSF in India and its activities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;FSF-India would be soon launching a fellowship programme and details about&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;the same ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsf.org.in/new/fellowship&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsf.org.in/new/fellowship&#34;&gt;http://www.fsf.org.in/new/fellowship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;are there on the website.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;It was not too difficult to let people know about the GNU project.A lot of&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;people were curious as to what we&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;were doing on the stall.We gladly told that we had put it up as volunteers&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;to FSF-India.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Apart from working on the stall we had one more bonus,very good internet&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;connectivity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Got sarge working on both the machines on the stall and then i set out a&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;small task for myself.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;All three days except the first day i was hacking on GCJ and trying to get&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;it working with SWT/GTK&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I had to compile it from source as the linking was not done with gcj 4.0.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Once i got SWT working i moved ahead to java-gnome.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Getting java-gnome to work was not that tough either.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;So now i had a small image viewer working with java-gnome compiled into&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;native binary(linked to libgcj offcourse).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;A complete free java application.( No not yet )&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;We had only one Cat5 LAN cable in the stall so only one machine from the&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;stall could be on the network at any time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Eclipse has made immense progress in combination with GCJ.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;You can get native applications from GCJ fairly quick.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Got Java skills , go ahead , try out GCJ.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The very next stall to FSF-India was of the Phoenix project (&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsc.res.in/%7Eelab/phoenix/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsc.res.in/~elab/phoenix/&#34;&gt;http://www.nsc.res.in/~elab/phoenix/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Pramode ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.livejournal.com/users/pramode_ce/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.livejournal.com/users/pramode_ce/&#34;&gt;http://www.livejournal.com/users/pramode_ce/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ) was the person&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;behind this project being presented&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;at FOSS.IN. The project showed how to perform simple experiments using&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;locally available hardware and a few&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;programs in python.The project has a lot of interest and it would be very&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;good for a lo
    t of LABs (Schools, Coleges etc.) to&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;implement it.Prof. Vasant Barve ( now retired ) was there too as a&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;delegate.He mentioned about his programs written in TC.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;We asked him if he had named his project and whether he was interested in&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;porting them to GNU/Linux.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;He is indeed very much interested.Pramod took this oppurtunity of&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;introducing SPACE to Prof. Barve.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Prof.Barve used to teach at College of Engineering in Pune and some other&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;colleges from 1967 onwards.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The College of engineering in Pune has its own long heritage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;A lot of CDAC engineers knew/know Prof.Barve very well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;It would be really nice to have the programs/experiments available on&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;GNU/Linux.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Physics/Mechanics teachers and students both would benefit a lot from these&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;programs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The software is not yet named , Prof. Barve calls it Virtual Laboratory,&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;lets see what name it takes here on.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The closing of the conference was also very interesting in a number of ways.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Volker&amp;rsquo;s talk on Creative Commons was really informative.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;He explained the various forms of commons.The social structure etc. etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Than he went on to tell about the effect of copyleft (GNU GPL) and the GNU&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Project on the various other&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;forms of media.The formation of the creative commons and content available&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;under&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;the creative commons.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Incidently the FOSS.IN DVD has music available under the Creative Commons&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Free Software has changed the way a lot of things are done in this world.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Next Atul took onto the stage to announce the closure with a couple of&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;interesting details.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;He introduced the entire team which was responsible for FOSS.IN and they&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;lined up near the stage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Than came the list of the speakers , a whopping one at that.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The speakers when lined up showed that it was not he/him or her that were&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;making the difference.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The difference was made by us all.We the people.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Copyright &amp;copy; 2005 Kanti Jadia&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article are permitted&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;worldwide without royalty in any medium provided this notice is preserved&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS.IN/2005 a report</title>
      <link>http://jkantihub.github.io/fossin2005-a-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 08:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jkantihub.github.io/fossin2005-a-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_FOSS.IN/2005 - Report&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thejadias.org/blog/&#34;&gt;http://www.thejadias.org/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event formally known as LB or LinuxBangalore got a new name and a newvenue this year.What could be more appropriate than the historical Bangalore Palace to holdthe conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ( me and Praveen A ) had planned to put a stall for FSF-India at FOSS.IN.I was never keen on putting a demo as i believe that the whole of FOSS.INdemoedFree Software a lot.A lot of it infact as this was FOSS.IN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the venue on 29th Morning around 8:15.Praveen had registered for a lot of volunteering and also helped some in theconference as well.He got in touch with Tejas and got right inside the registration counter tohelp out.( &lt;a href=&#34;http://people.redhat.com/jmorris/images/fossinmisc2.jpg&#34;&gt;http://people.redhat.com/jmorris/images/fossinmisc2.jpg&lt;/a&gt; ).Praveen wearing the &amp;ldquo;Freedom Matters&amp;rdquo; T-Shirt.Would upload the images insome time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format of the FOSS expo area was known to us and the idea of a stall wasa bit off.I got myself registered as a delegate and headed straight to the FOSS Expoarea.The FOSS Expo area had nobody in at that time so i headed to Intel hall (750 seater ).As i was moving towards the hall i met Gaurav Nawani.Gaurav mentioned that he would be putting up a demo of Blender in the FOSSExpo Area.He mentioned that he and his elder brother run a company (IronCode) and theymake games.I enquired as to what kind of games they wrote and he mentioned casualgames.The kind of games you enjoy playing in your liesure time.We both went inside the hall and sat there for the opening to be announced&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference was opened with the lighting up of a lamp ( having five sides) , traditionallycalled a Samai ( Sa-Maa-eeee ), by representatives of various GLUGs acrossIndia ( 5 ).The conference theme was very well described by the following poem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where The Mind is Without FearFrom Rabindranath Tagore&amp;rsquo;s Geetanjali——————————————————–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where the mind is without fearAnd the head is held highWhere knowledge is freeWhere the world has not been broken upInto fragments by narrow domestic wallsWhere words come out from the depth of truthWhere tireless striving stretches its arms towards perfectionWhere the clear stream of reason has not lost its wayInto the dreary desert sand of dead habitWhere the mind is led forward by theeInto ever-widening thought and actionInto that heaven of freedom, my Father, let my country awake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first keynote was given by Alan Cox on the relevance of getting involvedwith Free Software.The red coloured cap (hat) worn by Alan was quite evident and only when hereached the end of the keynote didhe remove it.The cap was visible for all four days of the event and you weresure to see Alan every once in a while.The most interesting part of the talk for me was the part where he mentionedthat you can justget involved with a web browser and an email account.Where do you find this small a need to get involved with any sort ofproject.The benefits of working with FOSS projects are immense.Apart from programming skills which you gain you get to know a lot ofdifferent people.You learn how to interact with people from various cultures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the keynote by Alan got through i walked in straight to the FOSS ExpoArea.Karunakar was already there with 3 machines being put up for IndLinuxproject.Next to the IndLinux machines was a demo of LTSP put up by ILUG-DELHI guys.Gaurav was along with me as well looking where to put his Blenderdemo.Wegot 3 machines and got them unpacked.I went ahead and put the GNU &amp;amp; Penguin sticker on one of the machines fromthe ones i had.After a bit of groupalla ( get together ), we had the machines ready.I had a couple of posters with me which and brouchers for FSF-India andSPACE.A small lesson , do not expect to find gum/sticking/pins etc near the venue.Saw Kartik Mistry putting the Debian poster and so ran out to get somecellotape/pins from him.A lot of people were around including Karunakar,Jaldhar , Mahesh Pai, GoraMohanty, Pramode, Arjun etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around afternoon i saw Alan coming inside the FOSS Expo Area, and in afew mins he was not to be seen.After some time Atul appeared and requested that the FOSS Expo area wouldalso move to the Conference Expo area.We thought we would all move the out in the morning and than in a flash wewere all out that area.By this time Amol and Sameer came in too from Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a dedicated stall for FSF-India and this meant we were back to wherewe started.We got the machines in place and then got a few posters put as well.Anush was very keen on getting those posters as he felt they were veryimpressive( Indeed they are ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All along the four days we were kind of doing a round robin on the FSF-Indiastall.Sometimes it was me , sometimes Amol, another time Sameer and offcoursePraveen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Praveen was sharing with me some details on the talks going on in theBallroom as he was the hall marshal there.In all i attended around six/seven talks/bofs.The food was good with you paying in paper coupens(with options ofSouth/North Indian and Pizzas ).The T-Shirt also was is good and i hope it hangs around upto next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am surprised at the low amount of information people have about FSF.People do not even know where gcc came from.I was kind of letting people know about FSF in India and its activities.FSF-India would be soon launching a fellowship programme and details aboutthe same ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsf.org.in/new/fellowship&#34;&gt;http://www.fsf.org.in/new/fellowship&lt;/a&gt; )are there on the website.It was not too difficult to let people know about the GNU project.A lot ofpeople were curious as to what wewere doing on the stall.We gladly told that we had put it up as volunteersto FSF-India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from working on the stall we had one more bonus,very good internetconnectivity.Got sarge working on both the machines on the stall and then i set out asmall task for myself.All three days except the first day i was hacking on GCJ and trying to getit working with SWT/GTKI had to compile it from source as the linking was not done with gcj 4.0.Once i got SWT working i moved ahead to java-gnome.Getting java-gnome to work was not that tough either.So now i had a small image viewer working with java-gnome compiled intonative binary(linked to libgcj offcourse).A complete free java application.( No not yet )We had only one Cat5 LAN cable in the stall so only one machine from thestall could be on the network at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eclipse has made immense progress in combination with GCJ.You can get native applications from GCJ fairly quick.Got Java skills , go ahead , try out GCJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very next stall to FSF-India was of the Phoenix project (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsc.res.in/%7Eelab/phoenix/&#34;&gt;http://www.nsc.res.in/~elab/phoenix/&lt;/a&gt;)Pramode ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.livejournal.com/users/pramode_ce/&#34;&gt;http://www.livejournal.com/users/pramode_ce/&lt;/a&gt; ) was the personbehind this project being presentedat FOSS.IN. The project showed how to perform simple experiments usinglocally available hardware and a fewprograms in python.The project has a lot of interest and it would be verygood for a lot of LABs (Schools, Coleges etc.) toimplement it.Prof. Vasant Barve ( now retired ) was there too as adelegate.He mentioned about his programs written in TC.We asked him if he had named his project and whether he was interested inporting them to GNU/Linux.He is indeed very much interested.Pramod took this oppurtunity ofintroducing SPACE to Prof. Barve.Prof.Barve used to teach at College of Engineering in Pune and some othercolleges from 1967 onwards.The College of engineering in Pune has its own long heritage.A lot of CDAC engineers knew/know Prof.Barve very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be really nice to have the programs/experiments available onGNU/Linux.Physics/Mechanics teachers and students both would benefit a lot from theseprograms.The software is not yet named , Prof. Barve calls it Virtual Laboratory,lets see what name it takes here on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closing of the conference was also very interesting in a number of ways.Volker&amp;rsquo;s talk on Creative Commons was really informative.He explained the various forms of commons.The social structure etc. etc.Than he went on to tell about the effect of copyleft (GNU GPL) and the GNUProject on the various otherforms of media.The formation of the creative commons and content availableunderthe creative commons.Incidently the FOSS.IN DVD has music available under the Creative CommonsFree Software has changed the way a lot of things are done in this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Atul took onto the stage to announce the closure with a couple ofinteresting details.He introduced the entire team which was responsible for FOSS.IN and theylined up near the stage.Than came the list of the speakers , a whopping one at that.The speakers when lined up showed that it was not he/him or her that weremaking the difference.The difference was made by us all.We the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright &amp;copy; 2005 Kanti JadiaVerbatim copying and distribution of this entire article are permittedworldwide without royalty in any medium provided this notice is preserved_&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>